const o={question:"Animal nacional",answer:"Águila real",options:["Burro","Caballo","Serpiente"],type:"choice",id:"03gm3o",en:{question:"National animal",answer:"Golden eagle",options:["Donkey","Horse","Snake"]},ru:{question:"Национальное животное",answer:"Королевский орел",options:["Осел","Лошадь","Змея"]},zh:{question:"国家动物",answer:"金雕",options:["驴","马","蛇"]}},t=Object.freeze(Object.defineProperty({__proto__:null,question:o},Symbol.toStringTag,{value:"Module"})),i={question:"¿Cuáles son los símbolos patrios?",answer:"La Bandera, el himno nacional y el escudo nacional",options:["La bandera, la charrería y el catolicismo","El himno nacional, la bandera y la virgen de Guadalupe","Los tacos, el tequila y la charreria"],type:"choice",id:"0j0ah7",en:{question:"What are the national symbols?",answer:"The Flag, the national anthem, and the national coat of arms",options:["The flag, charrería, and Catholicism","The national anthem, the flag, and the Virgin of Guadalupe","Tacos, tequila, and charrería"]},ru:{question:"Какие национальные символы?",answer:"Флаг, гимн и герб",options:["Флаг, чаррерия и католицизм","Гимн, флаг и Дева Гвадалупе","Такос, текила и чаррерия"]},zh:{question:"国家的象征是什么？",answer:"国旗、国歌和国徽",options:["国旗、马术和天主教","国歌、国旗和瓜达卢佩圣母","塔可、龙舌兰酒和马术"]}},n=Object.freeze(Object.defineProperty({__proto__:null,question:i},Symbol.toStringTag,{value:"Module"})),s={question:"¿A quién representan los senadores?",answer:"A las entidades federativas",options:["Al presidente de la republica","A jueces y magistrados","A los municipios"],type:"choice",id:"0uvmu",en:{question:"Who do the senators represent?",answer:"The federal entities",options:["The president of the republic","To judges and magistrates","To the municipalities"]},ru:{question:"Кого представляют сенаторы?",answer:"Субъекты федерации",options:["Президента республики","Судей и магистрата","Муниципалитеты"]},zh:{question:"参议员代表谁？",answer:"联邦实体",options:["代表共和国总统","代表法官和裁判","代表市镇"]}},a=Object.freeze(Object.defineProperty({__proto__:null,question:s},Symbol.toStringTag,{value:"Module"})),r={question:"Estructura del Poder Judicial Mexicano",answer:`Suprema Corte de Justicia
Tribunal Electoral
Los Tribunales de Circuito (Colegiados y Unitarios)
Juzgados de Distrito
Consejo de la Judicatura Federal`,type:"text",id:"12udrk",en:{question:"Structure of the Mexican Judiciary",answer:`Supreme Court of Justice
Electoral Tribunal
Circuit Courts (Collegiate and Unitary)
District Courts
Federal Judiciary Council`},ru:{question:"Структура Мексиканской судебной власти",answer:`Верховный суд
Избирательный трибунал
Окружные суды (коллегиальные и единичные)
Районные суды
Совет федеральной юстиции`},zh:{question:"墨西哥司法权结构",answer:`最高法院
选举法庭
巡回法庭（合议庭和单独庭）
地区法院
联邦司法委员会`}},l=Object.freeze(Object.defineProperty({__proto__:null,question:r},Symbol.toStringTag,{value:"Module"})),c={question:'En el Himno Nacional, la expresión "Más si osare un extraño enemigo" ¿Qué significa?',answer:"Sí un enemigo desconocido se atreviera",options:["Cuando un enemigo de la nación ataque","Los enemigos extraños son osados","Más de un enemigo esta al acecho"],type:"choice",id:"2igt9",en:{question:'In the National Anthem, the expression "But if a strange enemy dares" what does it mean?',answer:"If an unknown enemy were to dare",options:["When an enemy of the nation attacks","Strange enemies are bold","More than one enemy is lurking"]},ru:{question:'В Гимне Национальном выражение "Más si osare un extraño enemigo" Что означает?',answer:"Если бы враг неизвестный осмелился",options:["Когда враг нации атакует","Иностранные враги смелы","Больше одного врага подстерегает"]},zh:{question:"在国歌中，表达“如果一个陌生的敌人敢于”是什么意思？",answer:"如果一个未知的敌人敢于",options:["当国家的敌人攻击时","陌生的敌人是大胆的","不止一个敌人在潜伏"]}},u=Object.freeze(Object.defineProperty({__proto__:null,question:c},Symbol.toStringTag,{value:"Module"})),d={question:"¿Cuántos distritos electorales hay en México?",answer:"300",options:["32","500","128"],type:"choice",id:"40ihpn",en:{question:"How many electoral districts are there in Mexico?",answer:"300",options:["32","500","128"]},ru:{question:"Сколько избирательных округов в Мексике?",answer:"300",options:["32","500","128"]},zh:{question:"墨西哥有多少个选区？",answer:"300",options:["32","500","128"]}},p=Object.freeze(Object.defineProperty({__proto__:null,question:d},Symbol.toStringTag,{value:"Module"})),h={question:"Según la constitución, ¿Cuáles son los poderes máximos?",answer:"Ejecutivo, legislativo y judicial",options:["El presidente y las secretarías de gobierno","Los diputados y los ciudadanos","Tribunal Supremo de Justicia, Instituto Nacional Electoral y los cuerpos policiales"],type:"choice",id:"41ajni",en:{question:"According to the constitution, what are the highest powers?",answer:"Executive, legislative, and judicial",options:["The president and the government secretariats","The deputies and the citizens","Supreme Court of Justice, National Electoral Institute, and the police forces"]},ru:{question:"Согласно конституции, какие власти максимальны?",answer:"Исполнительная, законодательная и судебная",options:["Президент и министерства правительства","Депутаты и граждане","Верховный суд, Национальный институт избирательной системы и полицейские органы"]},zh:{question:"根据宪法，最高权力是什么？",answer:"行政、立法和司法",options:["总统和政府部门","国会议员和公民","最高法院、国家选举委员会和警察机构"]}},_=Object.freeze(Object.defineProperty({__proto__:null,question:h},Symbol.toStringTag,{value:"Module"})),b={question:"¿Cuándo fué creado el Himno Nacional?",answer:"13 de Septiembre de 1854",options:["10 de Septiembre de 1854","13 de Agosto de 1854","10 de Agosto de 1855"],type:"choice",id:"4wscae",en:{question:"When was the National Anthem created?",answer:"September 13, 1854",options:["September 10, 1854","August 13, 1854","August 10, 1855"]},ru:{question:"Когда был создан Гимн?",answer:"13 сентября 1854 года",options:["10 сентября 1854 года","13 августа 1854 года","10 августа 1855 года"]},zh:{question:"国歌是什么时候创作的？",answer:"1854年9月13日",options:["1854年9月10日","1854年8月13日","1855年8月10日"]}},q=Object.freeze(Object.defineProperty({__proto__:null,question:b},Symbol.toStringTag,{value:"Module"})),y={question:"¿Cómo se llama la ley fundamental de México?",answer:"Constitución Política de los Estados Unidos Mexicanos",options:["Constitución Mexicana","Libro de leyes de la república Mexicana","Reglamento Nacional de los Estados Unidos Mexicanos"],type:"choice",id:"5jhoxe",en:{question:"What is the name of the fundamental law of Mexico?",answer:"Political Constitution of the United Mexican States",options:["Mexican Constitution","Book of Laws of the Mexican Republic","National Regulations of the United Mexican States"]},ru:{question:"Как называется основной закон Мексики?",answer:"Политическая конституция Мексиканских Соединенных Штатов",options:["Мексиканская конституция","Книга законов республики Мексика","Национальный регламент Мексиканских Соединенных Штатов"]},zh:{question:"墨西哥的基本法叫什么？",answer:"墨西哥合众国政治宪法",options:["墨西哥宪法","墨西哥共和国法律书","墨西哥合众国国家条例"]}},g=Object.freeze(Object.defineProperty({__proto__:null,question:y},Symbol.toStringTag,{value:"Module"})),m={question:"¿Cuál artículo de la constitución habla sobre la libertad de expresión?",answer:"Artículo 6",options:["Artículo 9","Artículo 1","Artículo 7"],type:"choice",id:"5jnher",en:{question:"Which article of the constitution talks about freedom of expression?",answer:"Article 6",options:["Article 9","Article 1","Article 7"]},ru:{question:"Какая статья конституции говорит о свободе слова?",answer:"Статья 6",options:["Статья 9","Статья 1","Статья 7"]},zh:{question:"哪一条宪法条款谈到了言论自由？",answer:"第6条",options:["第9条","第1条","第7条"]}},f=Object.freeze(Object.defineProperty({__proto__:null,question:m},Symbol.toStringTag,{value:"Module"})),w={question:"Artículo de la constitución que prohíbe la esclavitud, habla sobre los derechos humanos y la discriminación",answer:"Artículo 1",options:["Artículo 3","Artículo 128","Artículo 10"],type:"choice",id:"7e79j",en:{question:"Article of the constitution that prohibits slavery, speaks about human rights and discrimination",answer:"Article 1",options:["Article 3","Article 128","Article 10"]},ru:{question:"Статья конституции, запрещающая рабство, говорит о правах человека и дискриминации",answer:"Статья 1",options:["Статья 3","Статья 128","Статья 10"]},zh:{question:"禁止奴隶制的宪法条款，谈论人权和歧视",answer:"第1条",options:["第3条","第128条","第10条"]}},z=Object.freeze(Object.defineProperty({__proto__:null,question:w},Symbol.toStringTag,{value:"Module"})),v={question:"Nombre oficial de México",answer:"Estados Unidos Mexicanos",options:["México","Estados Unidos del Sur Mexicano","República de México"],type:"choice",id:"7gml3a",en:{question:"Official name of Mexico",answer:"United Mexican States",options:["Mexico","United States of Southern Mexico","Republic of Mexico"]},ru:{question:"Официальное название Мексики",answer:"Мексиканские Соединенные Штаты",options:["Мексика","Соединенные Штаты Южной Мексики","Республика Мексика"]},zh:{question:"墨西哥的官方名称",answer:"墨西哥合众国",options:["墨西哥","墨西哥南方合众国","墨西哥共和国"]}},S=Object.freeze(Object.defineProperty({__proto__:null,question:v},Symbol.toStringTag,{value:"Module"})),A={question:"¿Cuándo son las elecciones presidenciales en México?",answer:"El primer domingo de Junio cada 6 años",options:["El primer domingo de Diciembre cada 6 años","El primer domingo de Enero cada 6 años","El primer domingo Febrero cada 6 años"],type:"choice",id:"7w0won",en:{question:"When are the presidential elections in Mexico?",answer:"The first Sunday of June every 6 years",options:["The first Sunday of December every 6 years","The first Sunday of January every 6 years","The first Sunday of February every 6 years"]},ru:{question:"Когда президентские выборы в Мексике?",answer:"Первое воскресенье июня каждые 6 лет",options:["Первое воскресенье декабря каждые 6 лет","Первое воскресенье января каждые 6 лет","Первое воскресенье февраля каждые 6 лет"]},zh:{question:"墨西哥的总统选举是什么时候？",answer:"每六年的六月第一个星期天",options:["每六年的十二月第一个星期天","每六年的一月第一个星期天","每六年的二月第一个星期天"]}},M=Object.freeze(Object.defineProperty({__proto__:null,question:A},Symbol.toStringTag,{value:"Module"})),j={question:'"Los Pinos”, en la capital de México, es el nombre de',answer:"Residencia oficial del presidente de la República desde 1934 hasta Noviembre 2018",note:"Desde 1 diciembre 2018 es un espacio abierto al público.",options:["Museo de arte revolucionario fundado en 1946","Parque urbano localizado en la alcaldía Miguel Hidalgo","Monumento nacional considerado patrimonio cultural de la humanidad por la unesco"],type:"choice",id:"86nw8",en:{question:'"Los Pinos", in the capital of Mexico, is the name of',answer:"Official residence of the president of the Republic from 1934 until November 2018",options:["Museum of revolutionary art founded in 1946","Urban park located in the Miguel Hidalgo borough","National monument considered a cultural heritage of humanity by UNESCO"],note:"Since December 1, 2018, it has been an open space for the public."},ru:{question:'"Лос Пинос", в столице Мексики, это название',answer:"Официальная резиденция президента республики с 1934 года по ноябрь 2018 года",options:["Музей революционного искусства, основанный в 1946 году","Городской парк, расположенный в административном районе Мигель Идальго","Национальный памятник, признанный ЮНЕСКО культурным наследием человечества"],note:"С 1 декабря 2018 года это открытое пространство для общественности."},zh:{question:'"洛斯皮诺斯"，在墨西哥城，是指',answer:"自1934年至2018年11月的共和国总统官方住所",options:["1946年成立的革命艺术博物馆","位于米格尔·伊达尔戈区的城市公园","被联合国教科文组织认定为人类文化遗产的国家纪念碑"],note:"自2018年12月1日起，成为向公众开放的空间。"}},O=Object.freeze(Object.defineProperty({__proto__:null,question:j},Symbol.toStringTag,{value:"Module"})),E={question:"¿Cuál es el artículo de la constitución que explica cómo puedes perder la naturalización?",answer:"Artículo 37",options:["Artículo 17","Artículo 57","Artículo 27"],type:"choice",id:"94xre7",en:{question:"What is the article of the constitution that explains how you can lose naturalization?",answer:"Article 37",options:["Article 17","Article 57","Article 27"]},ru:{question:"Какая статья конституции объясняет, как можно потерять натурализацию?",answer:"Статья 37",options:["Статья 17","Статья 57","Статья 27"]},zh:{question:"宪法中哪个条款解释了你如何可能失去国籍？",answer:"第37条",options:["第17条","第57条","第27条"]}},P=Object.freeze(Object.defineProperty({__proto__:null,question:E},Symbol.toStringTag,{value:"Module"})),T={question:"¿Qué dice la constitución sobre como debe ser la educación?",answer:"Laica, gratuita, obligatoria y de calidad",options:["Gratuita y de calidad","Obligatoria y de calidad","Laica y gratuita"],type:"choice",id:"97cwd",en:{question:"What does the constitution say about how education should be?",answer:"Secular, free, compulsory, and of quality",options:["Free and of quality","Compulsory and of quality","Secular and free"]},ru:{question:"Что говорит конституция о том, каким должно быть образование?",answer:"Светское, бесплатное, обязательное и качественное",options:["Бесплатное и качественное","Обязательное и качественное","Светское и бесплатное"]},zh:{question:"宪法对教育应该是什么样的规定了什么？",answer:"世俗的、免费的、义务的和高质量的",options:["免费的和高质量的","义务的和高质量的","世俗的和免费的"]}},C=Object.freeze(Object.defineProperty({__proto__:null,question:T},Symbol.toStringTag,{value:"Module"})),x={question:"¿Cuál artículo de la constitución habla sobre la libertad de trabajo?",answer:"Artículo 5",options:["Artículo 1","Artículo 4","Artículo 2"],type:"choice",id:"9qngj7",en:{question:"Which article of the constitution talks about the freedom to work?",answer:"Article 5",options:["Article 1","Article 4","Article 2"]},ru:{question:"Какая статья конституции говорит о свободе труда?",answer:"Статья 5",options:["Статья 1","Статья 4","Статья 2"]},zh:{question:"宪法的哪一条款谈到了工作自由？",answer:"第5条",options:["第1条","第4条","第2条"]}},N=Object.freeze(Object.defineProperty({__proto__:null,question:x},Symbol.toStringTag,{value:"Module"})),I={question:"Artículo de la constitución que trata sobre el derecho de petición",answer:"Artículo 8",options:["Artículo 10","Artículo 5","Artículo 6"],type:"choice",id:"aekgt",en:{question:"Article of the constitution that deals with the right of petition",answer:"Article 8",options:["Article 10","Article 5","Article 6"]},ru:{question:"Статья конституции, говорящая о праве на обращение",answer:"Статья 8",options:["Статья 10","Статья 5","Статья 6"]},zh:{question:"关于请愿权的宪法条款",answer:"第8条",options:["第10条","第5条","第6条"]}},F=Object.freeze(Object.defineProperty({__proto__:null,question:I},Symbol.toStringTag,{value:"Module"})),$={question:"¿Quién compuso la música del Himno Nacional?",answer:"El músico español Jaime Nunó",options:["El músico potosino Francisco González Bocanegra","El músico Dominicano José Perez Guardiola","El músico frances Charles Ferdinand Latrille"],type:"choice",id:"b1vwds",en:{question:"Who composed the music of the National Anthem?",answer:"The Spanish musician Jaime Nunó",options:["The musician from San Luis Potosí Francisco González Bocanegra","The Dominican musician José Perez Guardiola","The French musician Charles Ferdinand Latrille"]},ru:{question:"Кто сочинил музыку Гимна?",answer:"Испанский музыкант Хайме Нуньо",options:["Музыкант Франсиско Гонсалес Боканегра","Музыкант Доминикана Хосе Перес Гуардиола","Музыкант француз Шарль Фердинанд Латриль"]},zh:{question:"谁作曲了国歌？",answer:"西班牙音乐家哈梅·努诺",options:["来自波托西的音乐家弗朗西斯科·冈萨雷斯·博卡内格拉","多米尼加音乐家何塞·佩雷斯·瓜迪奥拉","法国音乐家查尔斯·费尔迪南·拉特里尔"]}},k=Object.freeze(Object.defineProperty({__proto__:null,question:$},Symbol.toStringTag,{value:"Module"})),D={question:"¿Cual artículo de la constitución dice que la educación es gratuita y obligatoria?",answer:"Artículo 3",options:["Artículo 1","Artículo 5","Artículo 2"],type:"choice",id:"b4mmhg",en:{question:"Which article of the constitution states that education is free and compulsory?",answer:"Article 3",options:["Article 1","Article 5","Article 2"]},ru:{question:"Какая статья конституции говорит, что образование бесплатно и обязательно?",answer:"Статья 3",options:["Статья 1","Статья 5","Статья 2"]},zh:{question:"哪一条宪法条款规定教育是免费的和义务的？",answer:"第三条",options:["第一条","第五条","第二条"]}},L=Object.freeze(Object.defineProperty({__proto__:null,question:D},Symbol.toStringTag,{value:"Module"})),R={question:"¿Cuánto tiempo dura el mandato presidencial en México?",answer:"6 años sin reelección",options:["4 años con capacidad de reelegirse sólamente 1 periodo más","4 años sin reeleción","6 años con reeleciónes indefinidas"],type:"choice",id:"bj2ii",en:{question:"How long is the presidential term in Mexico?",answer:"6 years without re-election",options:["4 years with the ability to re-elect for only 1 more term","4 years without re-election","6 years with indefinite re-elections"]},ru:{question:"Как долго длится президентский срок в Мексике?",answer:"6 лет без переизбрания",options:["4 года с возможностью переизбрания только на 1 дополнительный период","4 года без переизбрания","6 лет с неограниченным переизбранием"]},zh:{question:"墨西哥的总统任期多长？",answer:"6年，不得连任",options:["4年，可以连任1个周期","4年，不得连任","6年，无限连任"]}},J=Object.freeze(Object.defineProperty({__proto__:null,question:R},Symbol.toStringTag,{value:"Module"})),W={question:"¿Cuál de los símbolos patrios fue reconocido oficialmente en 1943 durante la presidencia de Manuel Ávila Camacho?",answer:"El Himno Nacional",options:["La Bandera","El Escudo Nacional","La Charrería"],type:"choice",id:"brvwv",en:{question:"Which of the national symbols was officially recognized in 1943 during the presidency of Manuel Ávila Camacho?",answer:"The National Anthem",options:["The Flag","The National Coat of Arms","Charrería"]},ru:{question:"Какой из национальных символов был официально признан в 1943 году во время президентства Мануэля Авила Камачо?",answer:"Гимн",options:["Флаг","Герб","Чаррерия"]},zh:{question:"在曼努埃尔·阿维拉·卡马乔总统任内，哪一个国徽于1943年被正式认可？",answer:"国歌",options:["国旗","国徽","马术"]}},U=Object.freeze(Object.defineProperty({__proto__:null,question:W},Symbol.toStringTag,{value:"Module"})),H={question:"¿Quién escribió la letra del Himno Nacional?",answer:"El poeta potosino Francisco González Bocanegra",options:["El poeta español Jaime Nunó Roca","El poeta veracruzano Ritchie Valens","El poeta colimense Jorge Solorzano"],type:"choice",id:"cufb4",en:{question:"Who wrote the lyrics of the National Anthem?",answer:"The potosino poet Francisco González Bocanegra",options:["The Spanish poet Jaime Nunó Roca","The Veracruz poet Ritchie Valens","The Colima poet Jorge Solorzano"]},ru:{question:"Кто написал текст Гимна?",answer:"Поэт Франсиско Гонсалес Боканегра",options:["Испанский поэт Хайме Нуньо Рока","Веракрусский поэт Ричи Валенс","Колименский поэт Хорхе Солорсано"]},zh:{question:"谁写了国歌的歌词？",answer:"来自波托西的诗人弗朗西斯科·冈萨雷斯·博卡内格拉",options:["西班牙诗人哈梅·努诺·罗卡","来自韦拉克鲁斯的诗人里奇·瓦伦斯","来自科利马的诗人豪尔赫·索洛萨诺"]}},B=Object.freeze(Object.defineProperty({__proto__:null,question:H},Symbol.toStringTag,{value:"Module"})),G={question:"Artículo de la constitución que habla sobre los extranjeros",answer:"Artículo 33",options:["Artículo 13","Artículo 23","Artículo 31"],type:"choice",id:"d00wke",en:{question:"Article of the constitution that talks about foreigners",answer:"Article 33",options:["Article 13","Article 23","Article 31"]},ru:{question:"Статья конституции, говорящая об иностранцах",answer:"Статья 33",options:["Статья 13","Статья 23","Статья 31"]},zh:{question:"关于外国人的宪法条款",answer:"第33条",options:["第13条","第23条","第31条"]}},Q=Object.freeze(Object.defineProperty({__proto__:null,question:G},Symbol.toStringTag,{value:"Module"})),V={question:"¿Cúal es el significado de el águila y la serpiente que aparecen en el escudo nacional mexicano, incluido en la franja blanca de la bandera?",answer:"Representan una leyenda prehispánica",options:["Representan una leyenda católica","Representan una pintura","Representan un ritual"],type:"choice",id:"e0akao",en:{question:"What is the meaning of the eagle and the serpent that appear on the Mexican national coat of arms, included in the white stripe of the flag?",answer:"They represent a pre-Hispanic legend",options:["They represent a Catholic legend","They represent a painting","They represent a ritual"]},ru:{question:"Каково значение орла и змеи, изображенных на национальном гербе Мексики, включенном в белую полосу флага?",answer:"Представляют собой предисловие",options:["Представляют собой католическую легенду","Представляют собой картину","Представляют собой ритуал"]},zh:{question:"墨西哥国徽中出现在白色条纹上的鹰和蛇的意义是什么？",answer:"它们代表了一个前哥伦布时期的传说",options:["它们代表一个天主教的传说","它们代表一幅画","它们代表一个仪式"]}},K=Object.freeze(Object.defineProperty({__proto__:null,question:V},Symbol.toStringTag,{value:"Module"})),Y={question:"¿Quienes crean y aprueban las leyes en México?",answer:"Los diputados y senadores del congreso de la unión",options:["Los ciudadanos por medio del voto","El presidente de la república","Los jueces y magistrados de la suprema corte de justicia"],type:"choice",id:"eksbft",en:{question:"Who creates and approves laws in Mexico?",answer:"The deputies and senators of the Congress of the Union",options:["Citizens through voting","The President of the Republic","The judges and magistrates of the Supreme Court of Justice"]},ru:{question:"Кто создает и принимает законы в Мексике?",answer:"Депутаты и сенаторы конгресса союза",options:["Граждане посредством голосования","Президент республики","Судьи и магистраты верховного суда правосудия"]},zh:{question:"谁在墨西哥制定和批准法律？",answer:"联邦国会的众议员和参议员",options:["公民通过投票","共和国总统","最高法院的法官和法官"]}},X=Object.freeze(Object.defineProperty({__proto__:null,question:Y},Symbol.toStringTag,{value:"Module"})),Z={question:"Artículo de la constitución sobre las obligaciones de los ciudadanos",answer:"Artículo 31",options:["Artículo 13","Artículo 30","Artículo 33"],type:"choice",id:"eopryv",en:{question:"Article of the constitution regarding the obligations of citizens",answer:"Article 31",options:["Article 13","Article 30","Article 33"]},ru:{question:"Статья конституции о обязанностях граждан",answer:"Статья 31",options:["Статья 13","Статья 30","Статья 33"]},zh:{question:"关于公民义务的宪法条款",answer:"第31条",options:["第13条","第30条","第33条"]}},ee=Object.freeze(Object.defineProperty({__proto__:null,question:Z},Symbol.toStringTag,{value:"Module"})),oe={question:"¿Cuándo fué declarado oficial el Himno Nacional?",answer:"1943 durante la presidencia de Manuel Ávila Camacho",options:["1950 durante la presidencia de Lázaro Cárdenas","1982 durante la presidencia de López Mateos","1945 durante la presidencia de Díaz Ordaz"],type:"choice",id:"eziegc",en:{question:"When was the National Anthem declared official?",answer:"1943 during the presidency of Manuel Ávila Camacho",options:["1950 during the presidency of Lázaro Cárdenas","1982 during the presidency of López Mateos","1945 during the presidency of Díaz Ordaz"]},ru:{question:"Когда был официально объявлен Гимн?",answer:"1943 год во время президентства Мануэля Авила Камачо",options:["1950 год во время президентства Ласаро Карденаса","1982 год во время президентства Лопеса Матеоса","1945 год во время президентства Диаса Ордаса"]},zh:{question:"国歌是什么时候被正式宣布的？",answer:"1943年，在曼努埃尔·阿维拉·卡马乔总统任内",options:["1950年，在拉萨罗·卡德纳斯总统任内","1982年，在洛佩斯·马特奥斯总统任内","1945年，在迪亚斯·奥尔达斯总统任内"]}},te=Object.freeze(Object.defineProperty({__proto__:null,question:oe},Symbol.toStringTag,{value:"Module"})),ie={question:"¿Cuál es el artículo de la constitución que rige la educación primaria y secundaria?",answer:"Artículo 3",options:["Artículo 1","Artículo 5","Artículo 2"],type:"choice",id:"f3k4k",en:{question:"What is the article of the constitution that governs primary and secondary education?",answer:"Article 3",options:["Article 1","Article 5","Article 2"]},ru:{question:"Какая статья конституции регулирует начальное и среднее образование?",answer:"Статья 3",options:["Статья 1","Статья 5","Статья 2"]},zh:{question:"哪个是管理初等和中等教育的宪法条款？",answer:"第3条",options:["第1条","第5条","第2条"]}},ne=Object.freeze(Object.defineProperty({__proto__:null,question:ie},Symbol.toStringTag,{value:"Module"})),se={question:"Algunas fechas conmemorativas en México",answer:`Día de la Candelaria - 2 de febrero
Día de la Constitución - 5 de febrero
Día de la Bandera Nacional - 24 de febrero
Natalicio de Benito Juárez - 21 de marzo
Aniversario de la Batalla de Puebla - 5 de mayo
Día de la Independencia - 16 de septiembre
Día de Muertos - 2 de noviembre
Aniversario de la revolución - 20 de noviembre`,type:"text",id:"fn8mv",en:{question:"Some commemorative dates in Mexico",answer:`Candlemas - February 2
Constitution Day - February 5
National Flag Day - February 24
Birth of Benito Juárez - March 21
Anniversary of the Battle of Puebla - May 5
Independence Day - September 16
Day of the Dead - November 2
Anniversary of the Revolution - November 20`},ru:{question:"Некоторые памятные даты в Мексике",answer:`День Свечи - 2 февраля
День Конституции - 5 февраля
День Национального Флага - 24 февраля
День Рождения Бенито Хуареса - 21 марта
Годовщина Битвы при Пуэбле - 5 мая
День Независимости - 16 сентября
День Мертвых - 2 ноября
Годовщина революции - 20 ноября`},zh:{question:"墨西哥的一些纪念日",answer:`烛光节 - 2月2日
宪法日 - 2月5日
国旗日 - 2月24日
贝尼托·胡亚雷斯诞辰 - 3月21日
普埃布拉战役周年纪念 - 5月5日
独立日 - 9月16日
亡灵节 - 11月2日
革命周年纪念 - 11月20日`}},ae=Object.freeze(Object.defineProperty({__proto__:null,question:se},Symbol.toStringTag,{value:"Module"})),re={question:"El tema dominante del Himno Nacional Mexicano",answer:"Una exhortación a la guerra defensiva",options:["Invadir otras naciones","Expandir el territorio","Atacar a los enemigos de la nación"],type:"choice",id:"fudy1op",en:{question:"The dominant theme of the Mexican National Anthem",answer:"A call to defensive war",options:["Invade other nations","Expand the territory","Attack the enemies of the nation"]},ru:{question:"Доминирующая тема Мексиканского Гимна",answer:"Призыв к оборонительной войне",options:["Вторжение в другие нации","Расширить территорию","Атаковать врагов нации"]},zh:{question:"墨西哥国歌的主旨",answer:"对防御战争的号召",options:["入侵其他国家","扩展领土","攻击国家的敌人"]}},le=Object.freeze(Object.defineProperty({__proto__:null,question:re},Symbol.toStringTag,{value:"Module"})),ce={question:"Según la constitución, la educación es obligatoria ¿En qué niveles académicos?",answer:"Educación preescolar, primaria, secundaria y preparatoria o bachillerato",options:["Educación primaria, secundaria y preparatoria o bachillerato","Educación preescolar, primaria y secundaria","Educación preescolar y primaria"],type:"choice",id:"fxlk4",en:{question:"According to the constitution, education is mandatory. At what academic levels?",answer:"Preschool, primary, secondary, and preparatory or high school",options:["Primary, secondary, and preparatory or high school","Preschool, primary, and secondary","Preschool and primary"]},ru:{question:"Согласно конституции, образование является обязательным. На каких академических уровнях?",answer:"Дошкольное, начальное, среднее и подготовительное или бакалавриат",options:["Начальное, среднее и подготовительное или бакалавриат","Дошкольное, начальное и среднее","Дошкольное и начальное"]},zh:{question:"根据宪法，教育是义务教育，在哪些学术阶段？",answer:"学前教育、初等教育、中等教育和高中或文凭教育",options:["初等教育、中等教育和高中或文凭教育","学前教育、初等教育和中等教育","学前教育和初等教育"]}},ue=Object.freeze(Object.defineProperty({__proto__:null,question:ce},Symbol.toStringTag,{value:"Module"})),de={question:"Descripción de la bandera, colores y elementos",answer:"Es un rectángulo dividido en tres franjas verticales de igual proporción, de colores verde blanco y rojo. El Escudo Nacional se encuentra al centro de la franja blanca. El color verde simboliza esperanza, blanco la pureza de los ideales y rojo la sangre derramada por los héroes de la patria.",type:"text",id:"gj9z7",en:{question:"Description of the flag, colors, and elements",answer:"It is a rectangle divided into three vertical stripes of equal proportion, in the colors green, white, and red. The National Coat of Arms is located in the center of the white stripe. The color green symbolizes hope, white symbolizes the purity of ideals, and red symbolizes the blood shed by the heroes of the homeland."},ru:{question:"Описание флага, цветов и элементов",answer:"Это прямоугольник, разделенный на три вертикальные полосы одинаковой пропорции, зеленый белый и красный. Герб национальный находится в центре белой полосы. Зеленый цвет символизирует надежду, белый чистоту идеалов, а красный кровь пролитую героями отечества."},zh:{question:"国旗的描述、颜色和元素",answer:"它是一个矩形，分为三条相等宽度的垂直条纹，颜色为绿色、白色和红色。国徽位于白色条纹的中央。绿色象征希望，白色象征理想的纯洁，红色象征为祖国牺牲的英雄们流下的鲜血。"}},pe=Object.freeze(Object.defineProperty({__proto__:null,question:de},Symbol.toStringTag,{value:"Module"})),he={question:"¿Dónde se hacen las denuncias del consumidor? o ¿Cuál es la institución de protección al consumidor?",answer:"PROFECO: Procuraduría Federal del Consumidor",options:["POFECO: Poder Federal del Consumidor","MINCO: Ministerio Nacional del Consumidor","MINPROCON: Ministerio de Proteción de los Consumidores"],type:"choice",id:"hz6m7r",en:{question:"Where are consumer complaints filed? or What is the consumer protection institution?",answer:"PROFECO: Federal Consumer Prosecutor's Office",options:["POFECO: Federal Power of the Consumer","MINCO: National Consumer Ministry","MINPROCON: Ministry of Consumer Protection"]},ru:{question:"Где можно подать жалобу потребителя? или Какое учреждение занимается защитой прав потребителей?",answer:"PROFECO: Федеральная прокуратура по защите прав потребителей",options:["ПОФЕКО: Федеральная служба по защите прав потребителей","МИНКО: Национальное министерство по делам потребителей","МИНПРОКОН: Министерство по защите прав потребителей"]},zh:{question:"消费者投诉在哪里进行？或者消费者保护机构是什么？",answer:"PROFECO：联邦消费者保护局",options:["POFECO：联邦消费者权力","MINCO：国家消费者部","MINPROCON：消费者保护部"]}},_e=Object.freeze(Object.defineProperty({__proto__:null,question:he},Symbol.toStringTag,{value:"Module"})),be={question:"¿Secretaría que se encarga de cobrar impuestos?",answer:"SHCP: Secretaría de Hacienda y Crédito Público",options:["SAT: Secretaria de Administración Tributaria","SAIM: Secretaría de Administracion de Impuestos","SENAT: Secretaria Nacional de Administración Tributaria"],type:"choice",id:"ivh34z",en:{question:"Which department is responsible for collecting taxes?",answer:"SHCP: Ministry of Finance and Public Credit",options:["SAT: Tax Administration Service","SAIM: Tax Administration Secretariat","SENAT: National Tax Administration Secretariat"]},ru:{question:"Какое министерство занимается сбором налогов?",answer:"СНКП: Министерство финансов и общественного кредита",options:["САТ: Федеральная налоговая служба","САИМ: Секретариат по управлению налогами","СЕНАТ: Национальный секретариат налогового управления"]},zh:{question:"负责征收税款的秘书处是什么？",answer:"SHCP：财政和公共信贷秘书处",options:["SAT：税务管理秘书处","SAIM：税务管理秘书处","SENAT：国家税务管理秘书处"]}},qe=Object.freeze(Object.defineProperty({__proto__:null,question:be},Symbol.toStringTag,{value:"Module"})),ye={question:"¿En qué año se declaró gratuita y obligatoria la educación elemental? / En qué año se fundó la Escuela Nacional Preparatoria y quién lo hizo?",answer:"El 2 de Diciembre de 1867 durante el periodo de Benito Juárez",options:["El 2 de Diciembre de 1850 durante el periodo de Ignacio Comonfort","El 15 de Diciembre de 1871 durante el periodo de Sebastián Lerdo de Tejada","El 09 de Diciembre de 1877 durante el periodo de Porfirio Díaz"],type:"choice",id:"j7k7wj",en:{question:"In what year was elementary education declared free and compulsory? / In what year was the National Preparatory School founded and who founded it?",answer:"On December 2, 1867 during the period of Benito Juárez",options:["On December 2, 1850 during the period of Ignacio Comonfort","On December 15, 1871 during the period of Sebastián Lerdo de Tejada","On December 9, 1877 during the period of Porfirio Díaz"]},ru:{question:"В каком году было объявлено бесплатное и обязательное начальное образование? / В каком году была основана Национальная подготовительная школа и кем?",answer:"2 декабря 1867 года в период правления Бенито Хуареса",options:["2 декабря 1850 года в период правления Игнасио Комонфорта","15 декабря 1871 года в период правления Себастьяна Лердо де Техада","9 декабря 1877 года в период правления Порфирио Диаса"]},zh:{question:"在什么年份宣布基础教育是免费的和强制性的？/ 在什么年份成立了国家预备学校，创办人是谁？",answer:"1867年12月2日，贝尼托·胡亚雷斯时期",options:["1850年12月2日，伊格纳西奥·科莫福特时期","1871年12月15日，塞巴斯蒂安·莱尔多·德·特哈达时期","1877年12月9日，波费里奥·迪亚斯时期"]}},ge=Object.freeze(Object.defineProperty({__proto__:null,question:ye},Symbol.toStringTag,{value:"Module"})),me={question:"¿Cuántos años dura la educación primaria en México?",answer:"6 años",options:["5 años","3 años","1 año"],type:"choice",id:"klh0xw6",en:{question:"How many years does primary education last in Mexico?",answer:"6 years",options:["5 years","3 years","1 year"]},ru:{question:"Сколько лет длится начальное образование в Мексике?",answer:"6 лет",options:["5 лет","3 года","1 год"]},zh:{question:"墨西哥的小学教育持续多少年？",answer:"6年",options:["5年","3年","1年"]}},fe=Object.freeze(Object.defineProperty({__proto__:null,question:me},Symbol.toStringTag,{value:"Module"})),we={question:"¿Cuánto dura el CICLO ESCOLAR primario en México?",answer:"1 año",note:"Es diferente a cuanto dura la primaria que son 6 años.",options:["2 años","3 años","6 años"],type:"choice",id:"klq3nh",en:{question:"How long does the primary SCHOOL YEAR last in Mexico?",answer:"1 year",options:["2 years","3 years","6 years"],note:"It is different from how long primary school lasts, which is 6 years."},ru:{question:"Сколько длится учебный год в начальной школе в Мексике?",answer:"1 год",note:"Это отличается от того, сколько длится начальное образование, которое составляет 6 лет."},zh:{question:"在墨西哥，初等教育的学年持续多久？",answer:"1年",options:["2年","3年","6年"],note:"这与小学的持续时间不同，小学是6年。"}},ze=Object.freeze(Object.defineProperty({__proto__:null,question:we},Symbol.toStringTag,{value:"Module"})),ve={question:"¿Qué documento rige a los extranjeros y mexicanos en el territorio nacional o que documento otorga derechos a los mexicanos?",answer:"Constitución Política de los Estados Unidos Mexicanos",options:["Constitución Mexicana","Libro de leyes de la república Mexicana","Reglamento Nacional de los Estados Unidos Mexicanos"],type:"choice",id:"l7gfov",en:{question:"What document governs foreigners and Mexicans in national territory or what document grants rights to Mexicans?",answer:"Political Constitution of the United Mexican States",options:["Mexican Constitution","Book of Laws of the Mexican Republic","National Regulations of the United Mexican States"]},ru:{question:"Какой документ регулирует иностранцев и мексиканцев на национальной территории или какой документ предоставляет права мексиканцам?",answer:"Политическая конституция Мексиканских Соединенных Штатов",options:["Мексиканская конституция","Книга законов республики Мексика","Национальный регламент Мексиканских Соединенных Штатов"]},zh:{question:"什么文件规范外国人和墨西哥人在国家领土上的行为，或者哪个文件赋予墨西哥人权利？",answer:"墨西哥合众国政治宪法",options:["墨西哥宪法","墨西哥共和国法律书","墨西哥合众国国家条例"]}},Se=Object.freeze(Object.defineProperty({__proto__:null,question:ve},Symbol.toStringTag,{value:"Module"})),Ae={question:"¿Cuántos diputados tiene el congreso?",answer:"500",options:["11","32","128"],type:"choice",id:"lusig",en:{question:"How many deputies does the congress have?",answer:"500",options:["11","32","128"]},ru:{question:"Сколько депутатов в конгрессе?",answer:"500",options:["11","32","128"]},zh:{question:"国会有多少名议员？",answer:"500",options:["11","32","128"]}},Me=Object.freeze(Object.defineProperty({__proto__:null,question:Ae},Symbol.toStringTag,{value:"Module"})),je={question:"El organismo encargado de regular la participación de los partidos políticos en las elecciones es",answer:"INE (Instituto Nacional Electoral)",note:"A partir del 4 de Abril del 2014, anteriormente era Instituto Federal Electoral (IFE).",options:["IFE (Instituto Federal Electoral)","CNE (Consejo Nacional Electoral)","CFE (Comisión Federal Electoral)"],type:"choice",id:"lycqq7",en:{question:"The organization responsible for regulating the participation of political parties in elections is",answer:"INE (National Electoral Institute)",options:["IFE (Federal Electoral Institute)","CNE (National Electoral Council)","CFE (Federal Electoral Commission)"],note:"As of April 4, 2014, it was previously known as the Federal Electoral Institute (IFE)."},ru:{question:"Орган, ответственный за регулирование участия политических партий в выборах",answer:"INE (Национальный институт избирательной системы)",options:["IFE (Федеральный институт избирательной системы)","CNE (Национальный избирательный совет)","CFE (Федеральная избирательная комиссия)"],note:"С 4 апреля 2014 года, ранее это был Федеральный институт избирательной системы (IFE)."},zh:{question:"负责监管政党在选举中参与的机构是",answer:"INE（国家选举委员会）",options:["IFE（联邦选举委员会）","CNE（国家选举委员会）","CFE（联邦选举委员会）"],note:"自2014年4月4日起，之前是联邦选举委员会（IFE）。"}},Oe=Object.freeze(Object.defineProperty({__proto__:null,question:je},Symbol.toStringTag,{value:"Module"})),Ee={question:"¿A qué edad se puede votar en México?",answer:"18 años",options:["16 años","21 años","19 años"],type:"choice",id:"lzieq",en:{question:"At what age can you vote in Mexico?",answer:"18 years old",options:["16 years old","21 years old","19 years old"]},ru:{question:"Во сколько лет можно голосовать в Мексике?",answer:"18 лет",options:["16 лет","21 год","19 лет"]},zh:{question:"在墨西哥，投票的年龄是多少？",answer:"18岁",options:["16岁","21岁","19岁"]}},Pe=Object.freeze(Object.defineProperty({__proto__:null,question:Ee},Symbol.toStringTag,{value:"Module"})),Te={question:"¿A qué entidad representan los diputados del Congreso de la Unión?",answer:"A los distritos electorales",options:["A los estados de la república","A los municipios","A las regiones del país"],type:"choice",id:"n34pze",en:{question:"Which entity do the deputies of the Congress of the Union represent?",answer:"The electoral districts",options:["The states of the republic","The municipalities","The regions of the country"]},ru:{question:"Какую сущность представляют депутаты конгресса союза?",answer:"Избирательные округа",options:["Штаты республики","Муниципалитеты","Регионы страны"]},zh:{question:"国会的代表们代表哪个实体？",answer:"选区",options:["代表共和国的州","代表市","代表国家的地区"]}},Ce=Object.freeze(Object.defineProperty({__proto__:null,question:Te},Symbol.toStringTag,{value:"Module"})),xe={question:"¿Cuánto dura la educación en México?",answer:`Preescolar: 3 años
 Primaria: 6 años
Secundaria: 3 años
 Preparatoria o bachillerato: 3 años`,type:"text",id:"njczl8",en:{question:"How long does education last in Mexico?",answer:`Preschool: 3 years
Primary: 6 years
Secondary: 3 years
High school or preparatory: 3 years`},ru:{question:"Сколько длится образование в Мексике?",answer:`Дошкольное: 3 года
Начальное: 6 лет
Среднее: 3 года
Подготовительное или бакалавриат: 3 года`},zh:{question:"墨西哥的教育持续多久？",answer:`学前教育：3年
小学：6年
中学：3年
高中或预科：3年`}},Ne=Object.freeze(Object.defineProperty({__proto__:null,question:xe},Symbol.toStringTag,{value:"Module"})),Ie={question:"¿Cuál artículo de la constitución trata sobre los derechos de los ciudadanos?",answer:"Artículo 35",options:["Artículo 15","Artículo 5","Artículo 53"],type:"choice",id:"pgb65j",en:{question:"Which article of the constitution deals with the rights of citizens?",answer:"Article 35",options:["Article 15","Article 5","Article 53"]},ru:{question:"Какая статья конституции говорит о правах граждан?",answer:"Статья 35",options:["Статья 15","Статья 5","Статья 53"]},zh:{question:"宪法中哪个条款涉及公民的权利？",answer:"第35条",options:["第15条","第5条","第53条"]}},Fe=Object.freeze(Object.defineProperty({__proto__:null,question:Ie},Symbol.toStringTag,{value:"Module"})),$e={question:"¿En que año se creó el INE?",answer:"2014",options:["2000","2011","2006"],type:"choice",id:"q1es7f9",en:{question:"In what year was the INE created?",answer:"2014",options:["2000","2011","2006"]},ru:{question:"В каком году был создан INE (Национальный институт избирательной системы)?",answer:"2014",options:["2000","2011","2006"]},zh:{question:"INE成立于哪一年？",answer:"2014",options:["2000","2011","2006"]}},ke=Object.freeze(Object.defineProperty({__proto__:null,question:$e},Symbol.toStringTag,{value:"Module"})),De={question:"¿Cuándo se fundó el IFE?",answer:"11 de Octubre de 1990",options:["11 de Marzo de 1990","7 de Mayo de 1986","14 de Noviembre de 1986"],type:"choice",id:"r45ra",en:{question:"When was the IFE founded?",answer:"October 11, 1990",options:["March 11, 1990","May 7, 1986","November 14, 1986"]},ru:{question:"Когда был основан Федеральный институт избирательной системы?",answer:"11 октября 1990 года",options:["11 марта 1990 года","7 мая 1986 года","14 ноября 1986 года"]},zh:{question:"IFE成立于什么时候？",answer:"1990年10月11日",options:["1990年3月11日","1986年5月7日","1986年11月14日"]}},Le=Object.freeze(Object.defineProperty({__proto__:null,question:De},Symbol.toStringTag,{value:"Module"})),Re={question:"Árbol nacional",answer:"Ahuehuete o árbol de tule",options:["Árbol de aguacate","Parota","Agave"],type:"choice",id:"r7s4yk",en:{question:"National tree",answer:"Ahuehuete or tule tree",options:["Avocado tree","Parota","Agave"]},ru:{question:"Национальное дерево",answer:"Агуэхуэте или тулевое дерево",options:["Авокадо","Парота","Агаве"]},zh:{question:"国家树",answer:"阿韦赫特树或图莱树",options:["鳄梨树","帕罗塔树","龙舌兰"]}},Je=Object.freeze(Object.defineProperty({__proto__:null,question:Re},Symbol.toStringTag,{value:"Module"})),We={question:"¿Quién es el máximo comandante de las Fuerzas Armadas?",answer:"El presidente de la república",options:["El Estado Mayor","El general en servicio de mayor rango en el ejercito","El titular de la Secretaría de la Defensa Nacional"],type:"choice",id:"sqxvrk",en:{question:"Who is the highest commander of the Armed Forces?",answer:"The president of the republic",options:["The General Staff","The highest-ranking active general in the army","The head of the Secretariat of National Defense"]},ru:{question:"Кто является верховным командующим Вооруженными силами?",answer:"Президент республики",options:["Генеральный штаб","Генерал с наивысшим рангом в армии","Руководитель Министерства национальной обороны"]},zh:{question:"谁是武装部队的最高指挥官？",answer:"共和国总统",options:["总参谋部","现役最高军衔的将军","国防部部长"]}},Ue=Object.freeze(Object.defineProperty({__proto__:null,question:We},Symbol.toStringTag,{value:"Module"})),He={question:"Artículo de la constitución que trata el derecho a buscar y recibir asilo",answer:"Artículo 11",options:["Artículo 10","Artículo 8","Artículo 20"],type:"choice",id:"tkott",en:{question:"Article of the constitution that addresses the right to seek and receive asylum",answer:"Article 11",options:["Article 10","Article 8","Article 20"]},ru:{question:"Статья конституции, говорящая о праве на поиск и получение убежища",answer:"Статья 11",options:["Статья 10","Статья 8","Статья 20"]},zh:{question:"宪法中关于寻求和接受庇护权的条款",answer:"第11条",options:["第10条","第8条","第20条"]}},Be=Object.freeze(Object.defineProperty({__proto__:null,question:He},Symbol.toStringTag,{value:"Module"})),Ge={question:"Los tres niveles de gobierno en México son",answer:"Federación, estado y municipio",options:["Primario, secundario y terciario","Ejecutivo, legislativo y judicial","Federación, delegación y provincia"],type:"choice",id:"to5cl",en:{question:"The three levels of government in Mexico are",answer:"Federation, state, and municipality",options:["Primary, secondary, and tertiary","Executive, legislative, and judicial","Federation, delegation, and province"]},ru:{question:"Три уровня правительства в Мексике",answer:"Федерация, штат и муниципалитет",options:["Первичный, вторичный и третичный","Исполнительная, законодательная и судебная","Федерация, делегация и провинция"]},zh:{question:"墨西哥的三个政府层级是",answer:"联邦、州和市",options:["初级、中级和高级","行政、立法和司法","联邦、代表和省"]}},Qe=Object.freeze(Object.defineProperty({__proto__:null,question:Ge},Symbol.toStringTag,{value:"Module"})),Ve={question:"¿Cuántos magistrados tiene la Corte Suprema de Justicia?",answer:"11",options:["32","500","2 por cada estado de la república mexicana (64)"],type:"choice",id:"u56wa",en:{question:"How many justices are there in the Supreme Court of Justice?",answer:"11",options:["32","500","2 for each state of the Mexican Republic (64)"]},ru:{question:"Сколько судей в Верховном суде?",answer:"11",options:["32","500","По 2 на каждый штат республики Мексика (64)"]},zh:{question:"最高法院有多少名法官？",answer:"11",options:["32","500","每个墨西哥州2名（共64名）"]}},Ke=Object.freeze(Object.defineProperty({__proto__:null,question:Ve},Symbol.toStringTag,{value:"Module"})),Ye={question:"Flor nacional",answer:"Dalia",options:["Cempazuchitl","Rosa","Margarita"],type:"choice",id:"vzfh9",en:{question:"National flower",answer:"Dahlia",options:["Cempazuchitl","Rose","Daisy"]},ru:{question:"Национальный цветок",answer:"Далия",options:["Цемпазучитль","Роза","Маргаритка"]},zh:{question:"国家花",answer:"大丽花",options:["万寿菊","玫瑰","雏菊"]}},Xe=Object.freeze(Object.defineProperty({__proto__:null,question:Ye},Symbol.toStringTag,{value:"Module"})),Ze={question:"¿Cuántos senadores hay en México?",answer:"128",options:["500","11","158"],type:"choice",id:"wp6sgq",en:{question:"How many senators are there in Mexico?",answer:"128",options:["500","11","158"]},ru:{question:"Сколько сенаторов в Мексике?",answer:"128",options:["500","11","158"]},zh:{question:"墨西哥有多少名参议员？",answer:"128",options:["500","11","158"]}},eo=Object.freeze(Object.defineProperty({__proto__:null,question:Ze},Symbol.toStringTag,{value:"Module"})),oo={question:"¿Quién es la canciller actual?",answer:"Alicia Bárcena",options:["Luis Videgaray","José Antonio Meade","Luis Ernesto Derbez"],type:"choice",id:"xj18wn",en:{question:"Who is the current chancellor?",answer:"Alicia Bárcena",options:["Luis Videgaray","José Antonio Meade","Luis Ernesto Derbez"]},ru:{question:"Кто является текущим министром иностранных дел?",answer:"Алисия Барсена",options:["Луис Видегарай","Хосе Антонио Меаде","Луис Эрнесто Дербес"]},zh:{question:"现在的总理是谁？",answer:"阿莉西亚·巴尔塞纳",options:["路易斯·维德加雷","何塞·安东尼奥·梅德","路易斯·埃内斯托·德尔贝斯"]}},to=Object.freeze(Object.defineProperty({__proto__:null,question:oo},Symbol.toStringTag,{value:"Module"})),io={question:"¿Quién imparte la justicia en México?",answer:"El Poder Judicial con división federal y estatal",options:["La policía en sus tres niveles, federal, estatal y municipal","El presidente y la camara de diputados","El senado de la república"],type:"choice",id:"xr1mfr",en:{question:"Who administers justice in Mexico?",answer:"The Judicial Power with federal and state division",options:["The police at its three levels: federal, state, and municipal","The president and the chamber of deputies","The Senate of the Republic"]},ru:{question:"Кто осуществляет правосудие в Мексике?",answer:"Судебная власть с федеральным и штатным делением",options:["Полиция на трех уровнях, федеральном, штатном и муниципальном","Президент и палата депутатов","Сенат республики"]},zh:{question:"谁在墨西哥实施司法？",answer:"联邦和州的司法权",options:["联邦、州和市三级的警察","总统和众议院","共和国参议院"]}},no=Object.freeze(Object.defineProperty({__proto__:null,question:io},Symbol.toStringTag,{value:"Module"})),so={question:"¿Cuál es el artículo de la constitución que habla del derecho de los pueblos indígenas? / Artículo de la constitución que establece una nación pluricultural",answer:"Artículo 2",options:["Artículo 1","Artículo 3","Artículo 4"],type:"choice",id:"xznx4k",en:{question:"What is the article of the constitution that talks about the rights of indigenous peoples? / Article of the constitution that establishes a multicultural nation",answer:"Article 2",options:["Article 1","Article 3","Article 4"]},ru:{question:"Какая статья конституции говорит о праве коренных народов? / Статья конституции, устанавливающая многонациональное государство",answer:"Статья 2",options:["Статья 1","Статья 3","Статья 4"]},zh:{question:"宪法中谈到土著人民权利的条款是什么？ / 规定多元文化国家的宪法条款",answer:"第2条",options:["第1条","第3条","第4条"]}},ao=Object.freeze(Object.defineProperty({__proto__:null,question:so},Symbol.toStringTag,{value:"Module"})),ro={question:"¿Qué órgano público otorga las cédulas profesionales?",answer:"Secretaria de Educación Pública (SEP) mediante la Dirección General de Profesiones",options:["La Universidad Nacional Autónoma de México (UNAM)","Ministerio Nacional de Educación (MNE) a través de la direccion general de profesionistas","Es facultad exclusiva del Instituto Politécnico Nacional (IPN)"],type:"choice",id:"yes4zc",en:{question:"Which public agency issues professional licenses?",answer:"Secretariat of Public Education (SEP) through the General Directorate of Professions",options:["National Autonomous University of Mexico (UNAM)","National Ministry of Education (MNE) through the General Directorate of Professionals","It is the exclusive authority of the National Polytechnic Institute (IPN)"]},ru:{question:"Какой государственный орган выдает профессиональные удостоверения?",answer:"Министерство образования (SEP) через главное управление профессионалов",options:["Национальный автономный университет Мексики (UNAM)","Министерство национального образования (MNE) через главное управление профессионалов","Это исключительное право Национального политехнического института (IPN)"]},zh:{question:"哪个公共机构颁发专业证书？",answer:"公共教育秘书处（Secretaria de Educación Pública，SEP）通过专业事务总局（Dirección General de Profesiones）颁发。",options:["墨西哥国立自治大学（Universidad Nacional Autónoma de México，UNAM）","国家教育部（Ministerio Nacional de Educación，MNE）通过专业人员总局（direccion general de profesionistas）","仅由国立 Polytechnic Institute（Instituto Politécnico Nacional，IPN）独有的权利"]}},lo=Object.freeze(Object.defineProperty({__proto__:null,question:ro},Symbol.toStringTag,{value:"Module"})),co={question:"¿Cuál es el organo depositario del Poder Legislativo?",answer:"El Congreso de la Unión",options:["El Presidente de la República","La Guardia Nacional","El Instituto Nacional Electoral"],type:"choice",id:"zvhp7",en:{question:"What is the depositary body of the Legislative Power?",answer:"The Congress of the Union",options:["The President of the Republic","The National Guard","The National Electoral Institute"]},ru:{question:"Какой орган является хранилищем законодательной власти?",answer:"Конгресс Союза",options:["Президент республики","Национальная гвардия","Национальный институт избирательной системы"]},zh:{question:"立法权的存放机构是什么？",answer:"联邦国会",options:["共和国总统","国民警卫队","国家选举委员会"]}},uo=Object.freeze(Object.defineProperty({__proto__:null,question:co},Symbol.toStringTag,{value:"Module"})),po=Object.assign({"./citizenship/03gm3o.ts":t,"./citizenship/0j0ah7.ts":n,"./citizenship/0uvmu.ts":a,"./citizenship/12udrk.ts":l,"./citizenship/2igt9.ts":u,"./citizenship/40ihpn.ts":p,"./citizenship/41ajni.ts":_,"./citizenship/4wscae.ts":q,"./citizenship/5jhoxe.ts":g,"./citizenship/5jnher.ts":f,"./citizenship/7e79j.ts":z,"./citizenship/7gml3a.ts":S,"./citizenship/7w0won.ts":M,"./citizenship/86nw8.ts":O,"./citizenship/94xre7.ts":P,"./citizenship/97cwd.ts":C,"./citizenship/9qngj7.ts":N,"./citizenship/aekgt.ts":F,"./citizenship/b1vwds.ts":k,"./citizenship/b4mmhg.ts":L,"./citizenship/bj2ii.ts":J,"./citizenship/brvwv.ts":U,"./citizenship/cufb4.ts":B,"./citizenship/d00wke.ts":Q,"./citizenship/e0akao.ts":K,"./citizenship/eksbft.ts":X,"./citizenship/eopryv.ts":ee,"./citizenship/eziegc.ts":te,"./citizenship/f3k4k.ts":ne,"./citizenship/fn8mv.ts":ae,"./citizenship/fudy1op.ts":le,"./citizenship/fxlk4.ts":ue,"./citizenship/gj9z7.ts":pe,"./citizenship/hz6m7r.ts":_e,"./citizenship/ivh34z.ts":qe,"./citizenship/j7k7wj.ts":ge,"./citizenship/klh0xw6.ts":fe,"./citizenship/klq3nh.ts":ze,"./citizenship/l7gfov.ts":Se,"./citizenship/lusig.ts":Me,"./citizenship/lycqq7.ts":Oe,"./citizenship/lzieq.ts":Pe,"./citizenship/n34pze.ts":Ce,"./citizenship/njczl8.ts":Ne,"./citizenship/pgb65j.ts":Fe,"./citizenship/q1es7f9.ts":ke,"./citizenship/r45ra.ts":Le,"./citizenship/r7s4yk.ts":Je,"./citizenship/sqxvrk.ts":Ue,"./citizenship/tkott.ts":Be,"./citizenship/to5cl.ts":Qe,"./citizenship/u56wa.ts":Ke,"./citizenship/vzfh9.ts":Xe,"./citizenship/wp6sgq.ts":eo,"./citizenship/xj18wn.ts":to,"./citizenship/xr1mfr.ts":no,"./citizenship/xznx4k.ts":ao,"./citizenship/yes4zc.ts":lo,"./citizenship/zvhp7.ts":uo}),ho=Object.values(po).map(e=>e.question);export{ho as questions};
